http://www.stlouisrams.com/privacy-policy

The Los Angeles Rams, LLC Website Privacy Policy
For our California Consumer Privacy Act notice, please click here: www.therams.com/ccpa_
Revised May 1, 2020
This privacy policy applies to the Los Angeles Rams' websites located at www.therams.com and the mobile application Los Angeles Rams (collectively, the "Services"). The purpose of this privacy policy is to disclose to you what information we may collect, how we may collect it, with whom we may share it, and certain other matters related to such information, including the choices you have regarding our collection of information and our use and disclosure to other parties of information we may have collected from you.
The Website is operated by our service provider Network Applications on behalf of The Los Angeles Rams, LLC (collectively, the "Los Angeles Rams", "we", "our", or "us"). Network Applications does not own any information submitted through this website and cannot use this information for its own purposes.
If you have questions or complaints regarding our privacy policy or practices, please contact us at website@rams.nfl.com.
If you have an unresolved privacy or data use concern that we have not addressed satisfactorily, please contact our U.S.-based third party dispute resolution provider (free of charge) at https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request.
When this privacy policy uses the term "personal information," we mean information that identifies a particular individual. When other information, such as a favorite team or player, is associated with personal information, it also becomes personal information for the purposes of this privacy policy.
Please note that the Services are directed towards users who reside in the United States. By using the Services, you consent to the collection, storage, processing, and transfer of your information in and to the United States, or other countries and territories, pursuant to the laws of the United States. While some of these countries may not offer the same level of privacy protection as your own, we commit to uphold the privacy protections as explained in this Policy.
Please read the information below to learn more about our data collection policies and practices.
1. Types Of Information That May Be Collected
2. How Information May Be Collected
3. How We Use The Information Collected
4. With Whom The Information May Be Shared
5. Security
6. Links To Other Websites
7. A Special Note For Parents Concerning Privacy
8. Notification Of Changes And Your Acceptance Of The Privacy Policy
9. Correcting/Updating Personal Information
10. Your California Privacy Rights
11. Questions About This Privacy Policy
Types of information that may be collected
The following are the types of information we may collect:
Information You Provide Us: In the course of using the website, we may ask you to provide us with certain information, including contact information, such as your name, mailing address, email address, phone number, fax number. birth date, gender, favorite Rams player, unique identifiers, such as your user name, password, demographic information, such as your date of birth, age, gender, education, household income, occupation, ticket holder status, game attendance, home ownership, marital status, or number of children, financial information, such as your credit card number, or similar information.
Tell-A-Friend:If you choose to use our referral service, called "Email This To A Friend" to tell a friend about our site, we will ask you for your friend's name and email address. We will automatically send your friend a one-time email inviting him or her to visit the site. The Rams do not store this information. It is for the sole purpose of sending this one-time email. If you believe that one of your contacts has provided us with your personal information and you would like to request that it be removed from our database, please contact us at website@rams.nfl.com.
Chat Rooms/Blogs/ForumsIf you use a bulletin board, chat room, blog or forum on theWebsite or within the mobile application, you should be aware that any personal information you submit there can be read, collected, or used by other users of these forums, and could be used to send you unsolicited messages. We are not responsible for the personal information you choose to submit in these forums. To request removal of your personal information from our blog or forum, contact us at website@rams.nfl.com. In some cases, we may not be able to remove your personal information, in which case we will let you know if we are unable to do so and why.
Site Usage Information: We may receive and store certain types of internet usage information automatically whenever you visit the Website, such as your browser type, click-stream data (pages, stories, etc.), browser type, Internet Service Provider, operating system, date/time stamp, and IP Address. For more details about how this information is used, please refer to "IP Address & Click-Stream Data" below.
Email Communications: When you open emails from us, we may receive a confirmation noting you opened the email, if your computer supports such capabilities. We also may keep track of what emails we send you and what emails you may be receiving from our subsidiaries and affiliates. Additionally, we keep a record of what communications you have opted to receive or not to receive.
Push Notifications: You may choose to receive promotional emails, newsletters, push notifications, and similar communications from us. You may opt out of receiving commercial emails from us by clicking on the opt-out or "unsubscribe" link included in the commercial e-mails you receive. You may opt out of receiving push notifications by turning off push notifications at the device level. Please note that opt-out requests may take some time to be effective. Your opt-out request will not apply to messages that you request or that are not commercial in nature. For example, we may contact you concerning any purchases you have made with us, even if you opt out of receiving unsolicited commercial email messages.
Co-Branding and Information from Other Sources: We may receive information about you from other sources and add it to the personal information we have collected. Examples of sources of this information include third party business partners and sponsors, offline promotions and sweepstakes operated by the Los Angeles Rams, the NFL and our sponsors; online promotions and sweepstakes operated by the Rams or our sponsors, such as the Coin Toss Captain; sponsored credit card application; and other Rams promotional activities or sponsored events. This information is used to fulfill the promotion or sweepstakes and contact the winner. Also, while participating in any of these promotions or sweepstakes, the user may choose to participate in other Rams offerings like the email newsletter or to receive a Rams merchandise catalog. In these instances we will use your information to send you the email or the catalog.
There may be times where co-branding relationships exist between the Rams and our business partners and sponsors. Examples include sweepstakes, surveys, and sale of Rams tickets and merchandise. When there is co-branding, the LA Rams information and branding will be displayed along with our business partner or sponsor's information and branding. By sharing your personal information in these instances, you agree you're your personal information may be used by the Rams and our co-branding partners. Any instance within our co-branding relationships where personal information is collected is voluntary, and you may choose whether or not to participate. If you have any questions or concerns about the disclosure of your personal information to our business partners and sponsors, please contact us at website@rams.nfl.com.
Here are some examples of our co-branding partners:
Season Ticket Account Manager:
https://am.ticketmaster.com/rams/
This page may be accessed by clicking 'Account Manager' under Tickets on the Rams site. This page is operated by Ticketmaster who handles some season ticket management and payment processes for the Rams. Ticketmaster also provides sale of Rams Single Game Tickets. While these pages are operated by Ticketmaster, Rams branding may be visible. When you submit your personal information to these pages, it is used by Ticketmaster to fulfill ticketing services for the Rams and ticket buyers. The information users submit on this page is subject to the Ticketmaster privacy policy, available here: https://www.ticketmaster.com/h/privacy.html?tm_link=tm_home_i_pp.
Rams Online Pro Shop:
https://www.ramsfanshop.com/
You may access this page by clicking on 'Rams Shop' from the Rams homepage or other places throughout the Rams website. The order fulfillment, customer service and credit transactions are handled by Fanatics Inc. through an agreement with the Rams. When users submit information to this page, it is used by Fanatics Inc. to fulfill merchandise services and perform customer service. Any information you submit on this site is governed by the Fanatics privacy policy, available here: https://www.ramsfanshop.com/help/privacy_policy. In some instances, we may receive certain personal information from Fanatics about users, in which case the Rams privacy policy also applies.
Mobile Application: When you download and use our mobile application, we automatically collect information on the type of device you use, operating system version, and the device identifier (or "UDID"). We use mobile analytics software to allow us to better understand the functionality of our mobile application software on your phone. This software may record information such as how often you use the application, the events that occur within the application, aggregated usage, performance data, and where the application was downloaded from. We do not link the information we store within the analytics software to any personal information you submit within the mobile application.
Geolocation: We collect your precise location-based information for the purpose of locating a place that you may be searching for in your area or to provide you with mobile application features based on your location. We will only share this information with our mapping provider for the sole purpose of providing you this service. You may opt-out of location-based services at any time by editing the setting at the device level or by emailing us at info@rams.nfl.com.
How information may be collected
We may collect information from you in several different areas on the Website, including but not limited to those described below:
Registration: You may be asked to complete a registration form and provide personal information; you may also be asked to choose a user ID and password in order to take advantage of certain features the Website may choose to offer, such as newsletters or contests. Participation in registration is voluntary and you will have the opportunity to decide whether or not to disclose information to the Website.
Single Sign On Services: You can log in to our site using sign-in services such as Facebook Connect, Twitter, or an Open ID provider. These services will authenticate your identity and provide you the option to share certain personal information with us such as your name and email address to pre-populate our sign up form. Services like Facebook Connect give you the option to post information about your activities on this Web site to your profile page to share with others within your network.
Newsletters and Website Emails: We offer free newsletters to share information with you about the Website, about us and our affiliates and subsidiaries, or about our marketing partners and advertisers and sponsors. You may receive a newsletter either by registering for a particular newsletter or in conjunction with a special feature or membership for which you have registered on the Website. Participation is voluntary and you will have the opportunity to decide whether or not to disclose information to the Website. You may also cancel your free email subscription by following the instructions provided on the Website or in the newsletter or email. You may contact the Rams Digital team to unsubscribe: website@rams.nfl.com
Contests or Sweepstakes: We periodically operate contests and sweepstakes through the Website that may require registration or the submission of personal information. Participation is voluntary and you will have the opportunity to decide whether or not to disclose information to the Website. Your personal information may be used to contact you for winner notification, prize delivery confirmation or other related purposes, (see the rules of each contest for details about how your personal information will be used). We may also ask your permission to allow us to publicly post some of your information on the Website, such as on a winner's page, in the event you win a contest or sweepstakes. Except as required by applicable law, we will not post your information without your permission. In some instances, a third party advertiser or sponsor may operate or host a contest or sweepstakes on the Website, and collect your information. Accordingly, we urge you to review the advertiser's or sponsor's privacy policy applicable to the contest or sweepstakes before participating.
We offer promotions that involve thirdparties to varying degrees. Here is how we treat user information in each type of promotion:
1. Promotions run solely by the Rams: In these cases, the Rams collect all relevant information from users such as name, email, mailing address, email type, favorite player, gender, birth date. In these promotions, the Rams privacy policy applies. The Rams do not share this information with any 3rd parties other than our service providers.
2. Promotions run by the Rams and third party sponsors: In these cases, the Rams collect all relevant information from users such as name, email, mailing address, email type, favorite player, gender, birth date. Users will be given the option to allow the third party sponsor to see their information. This option will be signified by checking a checkbox (opting in) that reads "Receive email from the Los Angeles Rams regarding special offers from the Rams and our partners." In these cases, the third party sponsor may see the information. Once the information is transferred to the third party, the third party's privacy policy also applies to your personal information when used by the third party.
Surveys or Voting: From time-to-time we may request personal information from you in conjunction with a survey or voting poll. Participation is voluntary and you will have the opportunity to decide whether or not to disclose information to the Website. We use this information to improve our products and services as well as to improve your experience with the Rams and our sponsors.
Games: When you register to play games on our Website, you may be asked to provide personal information.
Cookies: As with many Websites, our Services use a technology called "cookies." A cookie is a unique, random number that is stored in the browser on your computer. The cookie doesn't actually identify you, just the computer that is used to visit the site. Cookies automatically identify your browser to the Website whenever your computer is used to visit the Website. Cookies also let us know how many people visit our website and where visitors go on the site. In addition, cookies can let us know other information about you, like what web browser is being used to access the website. For registered users, cookies can make using the Website easier for you by saving information such as your passwords or preferences. By tracking how and when you use the Website, cookies help us determine which areas are popular and which are not. Many improvements and updates to the Website are based on data obtained from cookies. Accepting cookies allows you, among other things, to personalize your experience on the Website. Cookies may also allow the Website to present to you advertising which may be of interest to you. If you do not want information collected through the use of cookies, your browser should contain an option that allows you to disable or delete cookie data at any time. Some areas of the Website, however, may not provide you with a personalized experience if you have disabled the use of cookies. Cookies are associated with your personal information in our internal logs.
IP Addresses and Click-Stream Data: We may collect IP addresses and/or click-stream data. An IP address is a number associated with the service through which you access the Internet, like your ISP (Internet service provider), your company, or your university. At times, we also use IP addresses for purposes of system administration and to report aggregate information to our advertisers and sponsors, for example regarding the frequency with which our guests visit various parts of our sites. We may combine this information with other personal information. Click-stream data is information collected by our computers when you request Web pages from the Website. Click-stream data may include such information as the page served, the time, the source of the request, the type of browser making the request, the preceding page view and other such non-personal information. When analyzed, this data helps us analyze how visitors arrive at the Website, what type of content is most popular, what type of visitors in the aggregate are interested in particular kinds of content and advertising, and the like.
Third Party Tracking:
Our third party partners employ clear gifs (a.k.a. Web Beacons/Web Bugs), images, and scripts that help them better manage content on our site. We do not tie the information gathered to our Customers' or Users' personal information.
Behavioral Targeting/Re-Targeting: We partner with a third party ad network to either display advertising on our Web site or to manage our advertising on other sites. Our ad network partner uses cookies and Web beacons to collect information about your activities on this and other Websites to provide you targeted advertising based upon your interests. If you wish to not have this information used for the purpose of serving you targeted ads, you may opt-out by clicker here: http://preferences-mgr.truste.com/. Please note this does not opt you out of being served advertising. You will continue to receive generic ads.
Transaction Information: If you conduct a financial transaction with our Website, such as purchasing merchandise in our pro shop, purchasing tickets to promotional and community events, purchasing tickets through the Rams/Ticketmaster system or subscribing to services offered on our Website, we will ask you to complete an order form that will request certain information from you, including contact information, demographic information and financial information. We will use this information to complete the transaction that you have requested, i.e., to deliver the information, products or other services that you order, and to invoice you. For your protection, such information is collected and stored through encrypted means.
How we use the information collected
As applicable, the information you provide to us may be used to:
- contact you about the Website;
- contact you relating to your membership status;
- confirm or fulfill an order you have made;
- inform you of a prize you have won;
- monitor or improve the use of the Website;
- customize the advertising and content you see;
- monitor compliance with our terms and conditions of use of the Website; and
- send you promotional material or special offers on behalf of our marketing partners and/or their respective affiliates and subsidiaries and other third parties.
With whom the information may be shared
We may send you push notifications to your mobile device from time-to-time in order to update you about any events or promotions that we may be running. If you no longer wish to receive these types of communications, you may turn them off at the device level. To ensure you receive proper notifications, we will need to collect certain information about your device such as operating system and user identification information.
At times, we may share your personal information with others for various purposes. The following outlines the ways in which your information may be shared with others and the ways in which you may opt-out of having your information shared:
Third Party Service Providers: We employ other businesses, certain services and individuals to perform functions on our behalf. Examples include fulfilling orders, sending e-mail, removing repetitive information from customer lists, Website analysis, analyzing data, providing marketing assistance, processing credit card payments, and providing customer service. They may have access to your personal information needed to perform their functions, but may not use it for their own purposes, like sending you marketing offers about their products.
We may share your information with third-party business partners, for instance, for the purpose of enhancing our products and services or so they can market their products or services to you. This includes third party sponsors who may be involved with promotions offered and run by the Rams. If you do not want us to share your personal information with these business partners, please contact us at website@rams.nfl.com.
Aggregate Information: We may share aggregate information, such as demographics and Website usage statistics, with advertisers, sponsors or other organizations.
Third-Party Offers: Throughout the Website you may be presented with opportunities to receive special offers from third parties. An opt-in or opt-out message will allow you to select whether you would like your information to be shared for this purpose. By participating in these offers, you consent to allowing your information to be shared with third parties. When you allow us to share your personal information with third parties, we require third parties who have access to that information to agree to abide by our current Website privacy policy. However, we cannot control the privacy practices of these other companies, however, and you should review the privacy policies of any website you visit prior to providing your personal information.
Other Promotional Offers: We may send offers to you on behalf of our marketing partners. When we do this, we do not give that partner your name and address. If you do not want to receive such offers, you may:
Edit your profile online: https://preferencecenter.therams.info/Pages/Signup
Use an opt out link on the bottom of any Rams Email
Contact us at website@rams.nfl.com
Business Transfers:In the event that all or substantially all of our assets are sold or transferred to another party, or another transaction occurs in which your personal information is one of the business assets transferred, all personal information that has been collected and saved may be one of the business assets we transfer.
Administrative or Legal Process: We may disclose your personal information as required by law, such as to comply with a subpoena or other legal process, when we believe in good faith that disclosure is necessary to protect out rights, protect your safety or the safety of others, investigate fraud, or respond to a government request.
Links to other Websites
You should be aware that when you are on the Website you could be directed to other Websites beyond our control. For example, if you "click" on a banner advertisement, the "click" may take you off the Website onto a different Website. This includes links from advertisers, sponsors and marketing partners that may use the Website's logo as part of a co-branding agreement. If you submit personal information to any of those websites, your information is governed by their privacy policies. We encourage you to carefully read the privacy policy of any website you visit.
The Website may utilize framing techniques to make it appear that the user is still on the site when the user is actually on a third party Web site. For example when you use our Chat feature you will be taken to a third party site, but the page is framed with the Los Angeles Rams branding. Note that the third party's privacy policy governs the collection and use of the data collected on these pages.
Security
This Website incorporates reasonable safeguards to protect the security, integrity, completeness, accuracy and privacy of the personal information that we may collect and we have put into place reasonable precautions to protect such information from loss, misuse and alteration. Your personal information is transferred to our computers utilizing encryption software. Only those employees who need access to your information in order to do their jobs are allowed access. Our security policies are reviewed periodically and revised.
If you have any questions about the security of your personal information, you can contact us at website@rams.nfl.com.
A special note for parents concerning privacy
The Website is a general audience Website. We do not knowingly collect information directly from children under the age of 13. However, we do collect information about children under 13 from parents who provide consent on behalf of their children so they may sign their child up for our Kids Club. The information we collect is your child's name, date of birth and the address provided by a parent, guardian or purchaser of the Rams Kids Club membership. We use this information to allow you to sign your child up for the Kids Club and for you to receive Rams merchandise as a part of the Kids Club membership, for your child. If you no longer wish to allow your child to be part of the Kids Club or wish to delete all information collected about your child, please contact us at info@rams.nfl.com.
We will not share your child's personal information with any third party for any reason. If you feel we have collected personal information from your child directly, please contact us at the email address listed above to request immediate deletion of that information. We do not set any tracking technologies within the Kids Club section of the site that may be behavioral in nature.
The Internet offers children wonderful educational and entertainment resources. Your guidance and involvement are essential to help ensure that children have a safe and rewarding online experience. We encourage you to visit the Direct Marketing Association's Web Website (www.the-dma.org) and explore the Get CyberSavvy! Program as well as the GetNetWise Website (www.getnetwise.org) to learn more about parental control tools.
Changes to the policy
By using this Website, you signify your agreement to the terms of our privacy policy. We may amend this privacy policy at any time. If we make a material change to the way in which we collect, use, and/or share your personal information, we will post a notice on our website and / or send an email to users who have provided an email address. We will assume that you have given your permission for your information to be used under the terms of the new privacy policy, if you do not respond to our email within thirty days or continue to use the Website thirty days after a notice is posted. Please note that you should always update your personal information to provide us with a current email address. We encourage you to periodically review this page for the latest information on our privacy practices.
Access and Correction of Personal Information
Upon request, we will provide you with information about whether we hold any of your personal information. You may access, correct, or request deletion of your personal information by logging into your account or by contacting us at info@rams.nfl.com.
If your personal information changes or if you no longer desire to access our Website or receive our services, we will correct, update or remove the personal data you have provided to us. This can be done by the following methods:
1. Edit your profile online
2. Use an opt out message in a Rams email newsletter
3. Email us at info@rams.nfl.com
4. Write us at: Website Opt Out, Los Angeles Rams, 29899 Agoura Road, Agoura Hills, CA 91301
Please allow us ten (10) days to complete your opt out request. In addition, we will respond to all access requests including requests for deletion within thirty (30) days.
Data Retention
We will retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services. If you wish to cancel your account or request that we no longer use your information to provide you services contact us at questions@rams.nfl.com. We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.
Third-Party Ad Serving and Audience and Traffic Measurement Services: We may use third-parties to serve advertisements on the Services. These third parties may set their own cookies or similar web technologies to collect information about users' online activities over time and across different websites. To manage your preferences you may opt out here http://preferences-mgr.truste.com/. The Services may feature Nielsen proprietary measurement software, which will allow users to contribute to market research, such as Nielsen TV Ratings. Nielsen believes that you should have a choice about whether to contribute to our research and insights. To opt out of Nielsen measurement, you need only to activate the "Limit Ad Tracking" (for iOS devices) or "Opt out of Ads Personalization" (for Android devices) option in your devices settings. For web, please visit: http://www.nielsen.com/digitalprivacy to learn more about the Nielsen digital measurement products and your choices in regard to them.
Your California privacy rights
A California privacy law that went into effect on January 1, 2005, allows California residents to obtain specific information about a business's privacy practices if it shares information with other companies for those companies' direct marketing purposes.
As explained in this privacy policy, whenever you agree to let us collect personal information about you, we will always provide you with an option to prevent this information from being shared for non-administrative purposes with third parties. You can exercise this option at any time by following the steps outlined above.
Because this website has a comprehensive privacy policy and provides you with details on how you may opt-in / opt-out of the use of your personal information by third parties for direct marketing purposes, we are not required to provide you with this information. If you are a California resident and have questions about our compliance with this law, please send an email to website@rams.nfl.com or write to us at:
CA Privacy Rights
Los Angeles Rams
29899 Agoura Road
Agoura Hills, CA 91301
Questions about this privacy policy
If you have any questions about this privacy policy or the privacy practices of this Website, contact website@rams.nfl.com.
Questions regarding this statement should be directed to:
Digital Media Manager
Los Angeles Rams
29899 Agoura Road, Agoura Hills, CA 91301
(818) 540-4925
Advertising
Big left arrow icon
Big right arrow icon
Close icon
InstagramTwitterFacebookSnapchatShop IconProfile Overlay
AvatarAddAirplayArrow LeftArrow RightArrow UpArrow DownAudioBack 5sBack 10sBack 30sCalendarChartCheckDownLeftRightUpChromecast OffChromecast OnCloseClosed CaptionsBench OffBench OnBroad OffBroad OnVertical OffVertical OnCommentDockDoneDownloadDraftFantasyFilterForward 5sForward 10sForward 30sFull Screen OffFull Screen OnGamepassGamesInsightsKeyLeaveLiveCombineDraftFantasyMenu GamesMenu NetworkMenu NewsMenu PlayoffsMenu Pro BowlMenu ShopMenu StandingsMenu StatsMenu Super BowlMenu TeamsMenu TicketsMenuMore HorizontalMore VerticalMy LocationNetworkNewsPauseplayMultiple PlayersSingle PlayerPlaylistPlayoffsPro BowlPurgeRefreshRemoveReplaySearchSettingsShare AndroidShare Copy URLShare EmailShare FacebookShare InstagramShare iOSShare SnapchatShare TwitterSkip NextSkip PreviousStandingsStarStatsSwapTeamsTicketsVideoVisibility OffVisibility OnVolume HiVolume LowVolume MediumVolume MuteWarningWebsite
Caret downCaret upAt
The browser you are using is no longer supported on this site. It is highly recommended that you use the latest versions of a supported browser in order to receive an optimal viewing experience. The following browsers are supported: Chrome, Edge (v80 and later), Firefox and Safari.
Got it!
